# SHEA KEOGH

shealmk@gmail.com | 0838411548 | Dublin, Ireland https://sheakeogh.github.io

#### **SUMMARY**

Experienced Software Engineer with a passion for engineering and development. I am a hard worker who enjoys problem-solving and working both individually and as a part of a team.

Skilled in a myriad of different technologies for web applications and application development. Experience working with Java, Spring, Python, REST/SOAP API, Cloud Platforms - Pivotal Cloud Foundry(PCF) and Amazon Web Services(AWS).

# WORK EXPERIENCE

## Software Developer Consultant, Decision Inc. Australia

Feb 2024 - Sep 2024

- Led the design and implementation of an ETL solution, using Python, to support Australian State Governments with their financial processes.
- Provided troubleshooting and technical support, collaborating with clients to maintain full functionality of the solution.
- Enhanced existing software engineering standards and introduced new best practices within the development team to improve code quality and efficiency.

## Software Engineer, Mastercard

Sep 2022 - Sep 2023

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design, develop, and maintain complex Java based software systems, ensuring scalability and performance.
- Implemented new features and enhancements, leading to an increase in product functionality and improved user experience.
- Introduced automation testing and a new way of performance testing to Mastercard's APIs for improved monitoring.
- Conducted code reviews, identified and resolved bugs, and optimized codebase for efficiency.

#### Systems Platform Engineer Intern, Mastercard

Apr 2021 - Sep 2021

- Assisted senior developers in implementing new updates and support on call, gaining hands-on experience in software development practices.
- Conducted research on new technologies and potential changes to improve the team's work which were presented to the development team.
- Participated in peer reviews and contributed to the improvement of middleware.
- Gained exposure to project management and Agile methodologies, including daily stand-up meetings and sprint planning.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor of Engineering**Dublin City University

Sep 2018 - May 2022

• Electronic and Computer Engineering Major in Internet of Things.

## **KEY SKILLS**

#### **Technical Skills**

- Object-Oriented Programming
- Backend Development
- Java Spring Framework
- Python Development
- DevOps
- CI/CD

#### **Personal Skills**

- Effective Communication
- Collaboration
- Adaptability
- Problem Solving